# **Mohammad Ibrahim Israr**

israr.m.ibrahim@gmail.com ◆ www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-israr ◆ (949) 439-0010

# **Career Objective**

To utilize the knowledge and experience gained within my coursework and projects while acquiring my degree in Computer Science. I strive to learn the different areas of focus within the Technology domain and utilize the knowledge to enhance my abilities to grow within software engineering.

### Education

### California State University, Fullerton

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Expected Graduation Date: May 2024

#### Coursera, Google

Foundations of User Experience (UX Design) Completed: September 2023

### **Experience**

#### **Applied Medical**

Engineering Intern Summer 2023

- Collaborated with a team on creating a contraption that can grab onto a Trocar securely.
- Programmed microcontroller using Arduino, analyzing voltage data extrapolated from user input.
- Participated in design making process of contraption using SolidWorks.
- Presented a successful contraption demonstration to group of Mechanical and Electrical Engineers.

### ACM, Association for Computing Machinery, California State University, Fullerton

February 2022- Aug 2022

Secretary

- Oversee emails being sent from tech companies like NVIDIA, Microsoft, and Amazon
- Communicate with members regarding educational and career opportunities offered by these tech companies
- Participated in workshops related to algorithms, web-design, and the Agile methodology

### Muslim Youth Project, CA

Social Media Marketing Director

December 2021 - Present

- Ensure relevant information and creative content is broadcasted to families across SoCal so that MYP can further it's positive impact in the SoCal community
- Graphic Design, Project Management, Canva, Cross-functional Team Leadership, Public Speaking, Market Research, Brand Development, and MailChimp

### SoCal MIST, CA

Webmaster

October 2022 - May 2023

- Responsible for keeping SoCal MIST's website updated and relevant
- Optimizing the website to be viewed from multiple viewing platforms
- Created wireframe mockups to be approved by team before implementation of features
- Website bootstrapping using Create React App

### Salaam Corner | OCIF, Mission Viejo, CA

Committee Chair

March 2021 – December 2022

- Leading a team of like-minded individuals with strategic planning for events
- Programming weekly meeting agendas
- Annual Budget Planning
- Public Speaking
- Community engagement with other organizations

### Staples, Inc.

**Technology Associate** 

December 2018 - August 2020

- Demonstrated extensive knowledge in technology including all hardware, software, and applications.
- Evaluated customer needs and provided a variety of service options and product options to meet their needs
- Effectively communicated with customers, peers, and leadership to help drive business

### **Skills**

Programming: Python, JavaScript, React, SQL, PostgreSQL, C++, HTML, CSS, Arduino

Development Tools/IDE: Balsamiq Wireframes, Figma, Adobe XD, Arduino, Visual Studio Code, Virtual Box, Atom, Command Line,

Github

Relevant Coursework: Google UX Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Front-End Engineering, Python & C++ Programming,

Introduction to Cyber Security, Software Engineering, File Structures, & iOS Development

Leadership Skills: Public Speaking, Event Planning, Project Management, Root-Cause Analysis

## **Projects**

**Weather Application** Worked with a team to create a weather application using Kotlin. Played a key role regarding the creation of

UML diagrams and implementation. Several features implemented including push notifications, which can be

sent to user's phone depending on weather in user's location.

**SoCal MIST Website** Maintaining and updating a website that was built using React and is currently hosted using Firebase by

Google.

Health Webpage Created a webpage that features a collection of health and fitness photos using HTML5, JSON, and GitHub

**Pages**